Mss.530.1.Ar2.2 Mss.530.1.Ar2.2
American Philosophical Society
- Papers, 1923-1959; Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Sept. 10, 1931; 7x4-1/2; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) His visits at some of the National Parks and plans for visit at Madison.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Oct. 2, 1931; 11x8-1/2; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) Has visited Washington, D.C. Is in Princeton and reports on result achieved by Wigner on certain atoms.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Feb. 28, 1932; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    A.L.S.: Mully. 6p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics No.2.) Concerning the electronic structure of molecules.
  - Letter to [John Hasbrouck] Van Vleck, March 20, 1932; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Brillouin, Léon, 1889-1969
    Paris, France, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No. 2) Thanks for the review of his [Brillouin] book on quantum physics for students.
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Dyke [Vleck], Univ.of Wisc., March 28, 1932; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    Chicago, Typed L.S.: Mully. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) His ideas on molecular structure.
  - Letter to R. H. Fowler, Cambridge, Eng., May 21, 1932; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning a future publication by Condon and also possible translation by Brilliouin and wonders is he would like to publish them, since the Oxford Press does such beautiful mathematical printing.
  - Letter to P. Weiss, Alsace, France, Aug. 11, 1932; 11x8-1/2; Barnett, Samuel Jackson, 1873-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No. 2.) States his prior claim to "magnetization by rotation" and cites Einstein as acknowledging his claim.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Nov. 8, 1933; 9x7; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Sent his paper to the Royal Society and believes it was accepted. Conference on nuclei.
  - Letter to [Hendrik A.] Kramers, May 23, 1934; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning ferromagnetic anistropy.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], July 22, 1934; 9x7; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Plans for travelling in the U.S.West.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Sept. 20, 1934; 10-1/2x7-1/4; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Bryce Cañyon Nat. Park, Utah, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2. ) His adventures in the West.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Oct. 30, 1934; 10x8; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Would like to lecture at Cambridge. His travels in the West.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Feb. 13, 1935; 10x8; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Will fly to Boston to lecture and meet people.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Abigail] Van [vleck], Feb. 22, 1935; 10x8; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Thanks for the week-end. Describes his flight back to Princeton form Boston.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], March 25, [1935]; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    ca. A.L.S.: Mully. 4p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics No.2.) Discusses points at issue and the main point of "configuration method."
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], July 1, [1935]; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    Chicago, Ill., ca. A.L.S.: Mully. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics No.2.) Comments on his [Van Vleck] publication and suggests corrections and revisions, especially for work on electrons.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Oct. 14, 1935; 9x6; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) His travels in the Far East. His views on conferences. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Sept. 9, 1937; 11-1/4x9; Darwin, Charles Galton, Sir, 1887-1962
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 6p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) His ideas on Lars Onsager and the theory of magnets and dielectric fields.
  - Letter to [Sir] C[harles] G. Darwin, Cambridge, Eng., Sept. 28, 1937; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning Onsager and his theory.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Cambridge, Mass., Nov. 21, 1938; 11-1/2x8; Kronig, R[alph] de L[aer], 1904-
    Groningen, Germany, Typed L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning their work on atomic physics
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Cambridge, Mass., Sept. 23, 1957; 11-1/2x8; Casimir, H. B. G. (Hendrik Brugt Gerhard), 1909-
    Eindhoven, Netherlands, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Congratulates him on his evaluation of Becquerel and says that Kramers was helped by Becquerel.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], March 22, 1959; 11x8-1/2; Goudsmit, Samuel Abraham, 1902-
    Upton, Long Island, N.Y., Typed L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Quantum physics in the 1920's. Teaching physics today with little reference to the 1920's.